Guide to the New-York Historical Society Collection of Stereographs 1850-1964 (Bulk 1860-1900) PR 65
New-York Historical Society
- Geographic, 1850-1964
  - New Jersey--Morristown, [1870s] (Box 21)
    Morristown: a house that was Washington's Headquarters; building with tower (school or courthouse?); train at the D.L. & W. R.R. station; churches: Methodist Episcopal, Church of the Redeemer, First Presbyterian and a view from the First Presbyterian Church's burying ground of houses, a river and a bridge; the park and Soldiers' Monument; boats, including a sailboat on Speedwell Lake, and by the bridge at the head of the lake, and by a dam (?), Grand Island at Speedwell Lake; a map of Morristown.
  - New Jersey--Ocean Grove, [1870-1885] (Box 21)
    Identifier: PR-065-0185
    Ocean Grove: homes, hotels, boaters on a lake, a carriage in a pine grove, Sea House, including views on the piazza, from the piazza, looking toward the beach; group in front of the Mitchell cottage; Pilgrim's pathway, showing tents among the pines; St. John Island, Sunset Lake; group on the porch of the Park cottage; group on the porch of Camp View Cottage; group attending meeting on the beach; people swimming; a pier.
    30 items
  - New Jersey--Paterson, [1859-1910] (Box 21)
    Identifier: PR-065-0186
    Paterson, N.J.: general view of buildings and homes; Split Rock and bridge; Patterson rapids, with mill or factory; Passaic Falls; Centennial celebration: views of arches bedecked with greenery and mottoes, over the street, market St. Methodist Episcopal Church, right; parade on River Street; group of men, women and children in front of school (?); family in front of home; family portrait of woman and five children; family portrait, man, three women and three children; parents and three children, girl holding guitar; fire pumper in front of Cataract Firehouse; entrance to Roswell Colt's residence from the south side of the grounds, group standing on stairs; silk industry: washing silk, warping, weaving, printing color designs, finishing, and women folding rolls of finished silk.
  - New Jersey--Point Breeze, [1870s] (Box 21)
    Identifier: PR-065-0187
    Bonaparte's Park, Point Breeze: views of homes, including Prince Lucien Murat's, and a home built by a Mr. Becket in 1850; the Gardener's old house in the east part of the Park; the old Lake House; looking across Crosswick's creek at park; Old Hopkinson Mansion; the Old Wash House. For more information see: Bonaparte's Park and the Murats / by E.M. Woodward. -- Trenton, N.J.: MacCrellish & Quigley, 1879. 116 p., [2] leaves of plates: ill., port.; 24 CALL NO: \DC216\.5\.W89879
  - New Jersey--Shrewsbury, [1875] (Box 21)
    Identifier: PR-065-0188
    Shrewsbury, N.J.: children in road, group by house.
  - New Mexico, [1872-1899] (Box 21)
    Identifier: PR-065-0189
    New Mexico: "Frontier Ruffians" outside a saloon at the terminus of the A.T. & S.F. R.R., 140 miles S.W. of Albuquerque, view also includes a woman and four children; farmyard, possibly in N.M.; wagon in Cimarron Canyon; ox team on a street, made by an East Las Vegas photographer; Apache Pass, between Las Vegas and Sante Fe; general view, Grant; views in N.M. on the Denver and Rio Grande Railroad, including crossing bridges, and the Grand Canyon of the Rio Grande; view on the San Juan River.
  - New Mexico--Albuquerque, [1880s] (Box 21)
    Identifier: PR-065-0190
    Albuquerque: street views, including wagons, horses, burros and children, clock hanging outside business and signs for a hardware store and a newspaper; Albuquerque Indian School founded by the Presbyterian Board of Home Missions: group portrait of the faculty, children in uniforms lined up outside, interior view of the dining room, children seated at tables.
  - New Mexico--Indians, [1878-1885] (Box 21)
    Identifier: PR-065-0191
    Indians of New Mexico: cart at unidentified Pueblo; man with oxen and plow, man with oxen and cart, Tesque Pueblo; children by a rough wood fence; ruins at Cochiti; girls carrying water from the acequia, and men with burro laden with firewood, San Juan Pueblo; general view of Laguna, and two group portraits, probably made at Laguna of European man and Pueblo women, wives of he and his brother, with their children, and a group of Pueblo men; general view of Taos showing houses, ovens, and top of underground ritual structure; Zuni man on roof of Pueblo.
  - New Mexico--Mining, [1880s] (Box 22)
    Identifier: PR-065-0192
    Mining in N.M.: Los Cerrillos: general view of Carbonateville, and "Hungry Gulch" with miners cabin made of stones on side of gulch, and a prospecting party; Turquoise Mountain, and entrance to shaft of a turquoise mine.
  - New Mexico--Santa Fe, [1867-1888] (Box 22)
    Identifier: PR-065-0193
    Sante Fe: general views; street scenes, including view with wagon train from Mexico, burros with firewood and a business street, with various building identified, African American man with burro, children riding burros; the oldest house in Sante Fe; San Miguel church, including interior; San Francisco church; Church of St. Guadaloupe; San Miguel College; the Governor's Palace; public plaza, with monument; Apache Indians in front of government quarters; Mexican Americans in front of their home; a house with adobe oven next to it.
  - New York, [1870-1945] (Box 22)
    Identifier: PR-065-0194
    New York, views presumed to be N.Y., but with no further identification: hotel; an ice grotto; view in a glen, with tourists, waterfall and bridge; street scenes; hop pickers; views on the Erie Railroad at unidentified locations, including a locomotive and a bridge; winter view of an outlet to a lake in the "North Woods" of New York; an organ grinder by a Gazebo, made by a Cortland, N.Y. photographer.
  - New York--Adirondacks, [1865-1885] (Box 22)
    Identifier: PR-065-0195
    The Adirondack Mountains and vicinity: hunting camp; group playing croquet near Blue Mountain House; Adirondack and Arctic Hotels; Cascade House and the Hudson River; men and dogs outside home on Osprey Island; men with canoes at "the carry"; Thurman Station and the Hudson River; "looking up the lake from Martin's"; men in boat, North Branch of the Saranac River; Paul Smith's hotel on St. Regis Lake, including view from lake, men on piazza and at the boat house; men in canoe, Lower Saranac Lake; man sitting outside tent; small steamboat on Utowana outlet.
  - New York--Albany, [1860-1909] (Box 22)
    Identifier: PR-065-0196
    Albany, N.Y.: the old and new capitol buildings, with interior views of the New, and an image of the architectural model for the new capitol; street views: Broadway looking north, pedestrians in foreground, buildings draped with bunting and a banner mourning the death of Pres. Lincoln, looking up State Street; steamboat moored at People's Line dock; Hospital; Presbyterian Church, including interior view; general view showing industrial buildings and a bridge; row of homes; interior view of Green House at Van Rensellaers; the penitentiary; looking across the Hudson, possibly toward Albany from the east; railroad bridge; man with taxidermied cougars, Free Museum; Steamboat at dock, from the Hudson; men in buggy pulled by mule in the Park; Buffalo Bill parade, 1902, showing stagecoach, cavalry and Indians; Fulton's steamboat, the Clermont, at Albany during the Hudson and Fulton Celebration, 1909; a view of a canal in the vicinity of Albany, probably the Erie Canal near its outlet to the Hudson River.
    43 items
  - New York--Andes, [1880] (Box 22)
    Identifier: PR-065-0197
    Group portrait of men women and children, women holding walking sticks, made by an Andes photographer.
  - New York--Auburn, [1870] (Box 22)
    Identifier: PR-065-0198
    Auburn, N.Y.: Hardenburgh house, with gardens in foreground; old mill built by Mr. Hardenburgh; dining room, with table set with silver and crystal; Old First Presbyterians church, including interior views, including old Hardenburgh pew; fire station, men posing with engine and ladder out front; South Street; Auburn Prison: view of the grounds, and prisoners lined up marching to dinner.
  - New York--Ausable Chasm, [1870-1885] (Box 22)
    Identifier: PR-065-0199
    Ausable Chasm and vicinity: Birmingham Falls, views in the chasm, showing canyon, walkways and stairs built along it, boaters, sightseers, coach in front of Lake View House, and men outside log lean-to with brush roof.
  - New York--Beacon, 1959 (Box 22)
    Identifier: PR-065-0200
    Views from Mt. Beacon, including general views of Beacon and the Hudson River, and views of the hoist house and station of the inclined railway.
  - New York--Bear Mountain, 1959 (Box 22)
    Identifier: PR-065-0201
    Bear Mountain Inn: view of the front of the Inn and looking toward the Bear Mt. Bridge.
  - New York--Blooming Grove, [1880] (Box 22)
    Identifier: PR-065-0202
    Blooming Grove: Woodhull's Dairy, showing the herd, house, barn and other buildings.
  - New York--Bronxville, [1860] (Box 22)
    Identifier: PR-065-0203
    Bronxville: general view, showing homes and other buildings, a farm, and the river; view of a house with gated drive, and detail view of porch.
  - New York--Buffalo, [1868-1897] (Box 22)
    Identifier: PR-065-0204
    Buffalo, N.Y.: steamboat in icy harbor; Prof. King's Balloon Ascension, Sept. 16, 1873; Genesee St. with gas works; canal boats from shore to shore, taken from the Genesee St. Bridge; St. Joseph's Cathedral; St. Paul's Cathedral; Niagara St. from Main; Main St., showing trolley tracks, commercial buildings; Tifft House; Buffalo Savings Bank; General Hospital; horses with sledges outside snowy park; man with "ordinary" bike near the Terrace in the park; Camp Jewett G. A. R. encampment, 1897; group picnicking at Oakfield, Grand Island.
  - New York--Buffalo--Pan-American Exposition, 1901-1902 (Box 22)
    Identifier: PR-065-0205
    Pan-American Exposition: general view of buildings and fountains; Temple of Music where pres. McKinley was shot, including a night view, and views with crowds in front of the building; other night scenes, including illuminated fountains; the ambulance which took McKinley from the Temple of Music to the Hospital.
  - New York--Canals, [1880s] (Box 22)
    Identifier: PR-065-0206
    Unidentified canal scenes, possibly the Erie and/or Delaware and Hudson Canals, showing buildings along the side of the canals, a canal boat, and a bridge.
  - New York--Canandaigua, [1862-1874] (Box 23)
    Identifier: PR-065-0207
    Canandaigua, N.Y. and Canandaigua Lake: Canandaigua Hotel; steamboat Ontario, on the lake, at dock, after the fire; barge laden with goods sailing on lake; steamer Canandaigua, Bare Hill in background, and with farm fields in foreground; City Hall; Courthouse; general view from Courthouse; Gray Mansion, arbor in foreground; dock at Woodville; view at Pine Bank, showing steamboat and whaleback; arch over street welcoming firemen; a convent; East Gibson Street; bandstand in Atwater Park; balloon ascension on a major street; an unidentified large house; view at Sonnenberg, the photographer F.F. Thompson's home, showing ten pin bowling alley; a view of stumps in a wood. Most views are copy photographs, and the count includes duplicates. An original view has on verso the Amateur Photographic Exchange Club label.
  - New York--Cardiff, 1869 (Box 23)
    Identifier: PR-065-0208
    Cardiff: view of the Cardiff Giant, a hoax made of gypsum, and tent on W.C. Newell's farm where it was displayed, with visitors in front.
  - New York--Catskill Mountains and vicinity, [1859-1899] (Box 23)
    Identifier: PR-065-0209
    Views of the Catskills: mountain scenery, including valleys, some with mist; rivers, including men and building on the edge of Catskill Creek; Glen Mary near Scribner's saw mill; South Lake, Catskill Mountain, boater on lake; waterfalls, including Fawn's Leap in Kauterskill Clove, Bastion Fall, view from the top of Kauterskill Fall, and from below, Haines and other falls in Haines Ravine, Belle Falls, Palensville, waterfalls in Plauterkill Clove; the Spray House; roads in Kauterskill Clove; hotels, including Meade, Catskill Mountain House, Hotel Kaaterskil, Laurel House, Rip Van Winkle House Summer Hill House; rock formation called the Sphinx; Rip Van Winkle rock; Triton cave; a group picnicking and other sightseers; winter scenes including snowy scenes and icicles hanging from rocks, some delicately hand-colored; view from the top of Kauter5skill Fall, looking down the Glen, basket hanging from a pole over the abyss; general view of the village of Catskill.
    119 items
  - New York--Champlain Canal, [1940] (Box 23)
    Identifier: PR-065-0210
    Views along the Champlain Canal: the canal, locks from below, at both ends of the lock, and a view of the lake from the top of the locks, a view on the lake.
  - New York--Chautauqua Lake, [1880] (Box 23)
    Identifier: PR-065-0211
    Chautauqua Lake: women posing in front of "cottages, " including one with hammock on the porch; men standing next to tree with fountain of water coming from it; group of men from the S.S. [Sunday School?] assembly; sailboats and rowboats in front of Chautauqua Lake House; lake shore.
  - New York--Cohoes, [1870] (Box 23)
    Identifier: PR-065-0212
    Cohoe: from the prospect with Erie Canal in foreground; Cohoes Falls; machinery in Harmony Mills: wheel pit, and weave room.
  - New York--Cold Spring, [1865-1885] (Box 23)
    Identifier: PR-065-0213
    Cold Spring, N.Y.: St. Mary's Catholic Church; looking north on the Hudson from above the R.R. station; men and boats along the bank of the Hudson; looking across Hudson at Cro's-Nest; Indian Brook, near Cold Springs; railroad cut; Mount Taurus from Cold Spring; general view, with sailing vessel visible on river.
  - New York--Conesus Lake, [1875] (Box 23)
    Identifier: PR-065-0214
    Conesus Lake: group at foot of the lake, with boats moored to dock, and Case and Smith's in the distance; Case and Smith's Hotel at the edge of the lake; group on the porch of the Long Point Restaurant.
  - New York--Cooperstown, [1870-1885] (Box 23)
    Identifier: PR-065-0215
    Cooperstown: W. G. Smith's Photographic Block, with detail view of window display; Cooper Monument in Lakewood Cemetery; Leatherstocking's Falls; Leatherstocking's Cave; home of the daughters of J. Fenimore Cooper.
  - New York--Corning, [1880] (Box 23)
    Identifier: PR-065-0216
    Corning, N.Y.: women in doorway of Mrs. A.A. Blake Millinery.
  - New York--Cornwall, [1862-1885] (Box 23)
    Identifier: PR-065-0217
    Cornwall, N.Y.: general views, with Break-Neck and Polypus Island visible; steamer Mary Powell approaching Cornwall Landing.
  - New York--Croton, 1870s, 1959 (Box 24)
    Identifier: PR-065-0218
    Croton: Croton Dam and Croton Reservoir; Van Cortlandt Manor House.
  - New York--Crown Point, [1870-1889] (Box 24)
    Identifier: PR-065-0219
    Crown Point: a factory, possibly an iron foundry; group of women, with children seated at a table outside, corn filed beyond; ruins of the French fort, with Port Henry visible in background on one view.
  - New York--Dansville, [1870s] (Box 24)
    Identifier: PR-065-0220
    Dansville: "Our Home": view from Cottage St., showing house on hill near large structure, orchard in foreground; group at "Our Home," looking out over valley.
  - New York--East Greenwich, [1880] (Box 24)
    Identifier: PR-065-0221
    East Greenwich N.Y. U.P. Church Sunday School at Dionondawah Falls (group portrait of men, women and children).
  - New York--Elmira, [1868-1880] (Box 24)
    Identifier: PR-065-0222
    Elmira: Miss Haight with her horse and her dog; interior view of a church with motto "Now is Christ Risen from the Dead" painted on the wall.
  - New York--Fishkill, [1865-1875] (Box 24)
    Identifier: PR-065-0223
    Fishkill, N.Y.: Matteawan Creek, including view of five-story building next to the creek, and a factory building on the creek; Howland's Mansion, and a view from the Mansion toward Newburgh; view looking across the Hudson; long wharf, Fishkill Landing; Fishkill landing with Newburgh in the distance.
  - New York--Garrison, [1870] (Box 24)
    Identifier: PR-065-0224
    Garrison, N.Y.: St. Philips Church; ice blockade on the Hudson River at Garrison; looking through the cut on the railroad near Garrison; looking toward Garrison from across the river.
  - New York--Geneva, [1870] (Box 24)
    Identifier: PR-065-0225
    Geneva, N.Y.: people on the front porch of a home; Pultney Park, with fountain and bicycle; Hygienic Institute, with fountain in foreground; First Presbyterian Church.
  - New York--Glenham, [1870] (Box 24)
    Identifier: PR-065-0226
    View on the Matteawan at Glenham, showing small waterfall.
  - New York--Glenora on Lake Seneca, [1875] (Box 24)
    Identifier: PR-065-0227
    Views at Eden Glen, the summer home of F. L. H. Willis at Glenora on Lake Seneca: Eden Glen with pool and cascade; entrance to grounds; cottage; interior view; looking toward lake from parlor door; man and woman playing croquet; striped tent by the beach; the South Cover, overhung with trees.
  - New York--Glens Falls, [1870-1889] (Box 24)
    Identifier: PR-065-0228
    Glens Falls, N.Y.: group and carriage in front of the Friends' Church; group on deck of steamship with Glen's Falls Stage Co. poster on the side; bridge, shelf rock, and rapids; mill built by the English; Soldiers Monument; Rockwell House; Crosbyside, a house.
  - New York--Green Lake, [1880] (Box 24)
    Identifier: PR-065-0229
    Green Lake, or Kai-Yah-Koo Lake; view of the lake from resort area est. in 1876.
  - New York--Greenbush Heights, [1880] (Box 24)
    Identifier: PR-065-0230
    Greenbush Heights, N.Y.; W.P. Irwing flour mill on water fall above house with people and cow in the yard.
  - New York--Greenwich, [1875] (Box 24)
    Identifier: PR-065-0231
    Group in front of Barker's Grove School, Miss Mary A. Wilson, teacher, by a Greenwich, N.Y. photographer.
  - New York--Havana Glen, [1870-1910] (Box 24)
    Identifier: PR-065-0232
    Havana Glen, N.Y.: Waterfalls, gorges, bridges and stairways in the Glen.
  - New York--Herkimer, [1870-1909] (Box 24)
    Identifier: PR-065-0233
    Herkimer, N.Y.: Old Stone Church, with graveyard in foreground; portrait of two women, one holding stereograph viewer.
  - New York--High Falls, [1875] (Box 24)
    Identifier: PR-065-0234
    High Falls, N.Y. and vicinity: the falls from the north bank; Delaware and Hudson Canal from rock Lock looking north showing break made by the freshet; Jack Narrows from the east, canal in foreground; view in Jack's Narrows showing train.
  - New York--Honeoye Falls, [1865] (Box 24)
    Identifier: PR-065-0235
    Honeoye Falls: winter street view, wagon track down snowy street.
  - New York--Hornellsville, [1875] (Box 24)
    Identifier: PR-065-0236
    Hornellsville: Methodist Church with furniture set out in a park in the middle ground, and wooden debris in the foreground.
  - New York--Hudson River, [1859-1940] (Box 24)
    Identifier: PR-065-0237
    Views along the Hudson river, primarily in and near the Highlands: general views of the river, valley and mountains including a view with a basket of laundry in the foreground; the Highlands, including Crow's Nest, Storm King; Bulls Head and Break Neck; the Hudson River Railroad, including a view with the photographer's dark tent visible, and a winter view with snow; women on the banks of the river; roads along the river and in the valley; a building with a sign for wholesale grocers; stone wall; boats moored at stakes at Moodna, and covered bridge over the Moodna; photographer in a boat with a stereoscopic camera; boat tied up at Stony Point; man with camera, Break Neck Tunnel in the background; view from Breakneck with Polypus island in the distance; Clifton Point tunnel; S.W. view from Wm. B. Astor's house; on the Hudson near Poughkeepsie, bridge visible in the distance; Hudson River just below Ft. Edward; Buttermilk Falls, Parry House and old mill; a mansion with castelated towers; steamboat towing raft of barges; man fishing at creek; unidentified house, garden and conservatory; "moonlight on the Hudson"
    72 items
  - New York--Hudson River--Palisades, [1860-1885] (Box 24)
    Identifier: PR-065-0238
    Views of the Palisades on the west shore of the Hudson River in New York and New Jersey, including views of the cliffs, river and traffic, sightseers, a distant view of Yonkers from the Palisades, a group going boating, and a portion of the wreck of the Isaac Newton; view of the Palisades from Tuby Hook, with gazebo in foreground.
    44 items
  - New York--Ilion, [1880] (Box 25)
    Identifier: PR-065-0239
    Stereograph of a print depicting factories, products and partners of the E. Remington & Sons in Ilion, N.Y. Depicted are a woman sewing using the Remington sewing machine, firearms, agricultural implements, an iron bridge, and a steam car.
  - New York--Idlewild, [1860-1885] (Box 25)
    Identifier: PR-065-0240
    Idlewild, home of the artist N.P. Willis: the house, the river from the house, the ravine and a foot bridge over a creek.
  - New York--Ithaca, [1870-1885] (Box 25)
    Identifier: PR-065-0241
    Views of Ithaca and vicinity including general views of the town, Cayuga Lake, waterfalls, gorges, a tunnel at Fall Creek, a bridge in the gorge; distant view of a water cure establishment. Images by J. C. Burritt are signed in the negative.
  - New York--Kingston, [1881] (Box 25)
    Identifier: PR-065-0242
    Cement beds, Kingston, N.Y.
  - New York--Lake Champlain, [1860-1885] (Box 25)
    Identifier: PR-065-0243
    Lake Champlain: steamers on Lake Champlain, including the Adirondack, with an interior view of the stateroom and the Vermont; the Ticonderoga Hotel with stagecoach in front.
  - New York--Lake George, [1865-1885] (Box 25)
    Identifier: PR-065-0244
    Lake George, N.Y.: the lake, islands, mountains, and waterfalls; steamboats on the lake and moored, including the Horicon, Minnehaha; hotels including Katskill House, Horicon Pavilion; Trout Pavilion; tourists, boaters; Col. Ephraim Williams Monument near Bloody Pond; Old Fort William Henry, Cauldwell; view from Fort George; a street view; Prospect Mountain from the Lake, with churches in the middle ground; construction of the New York and Canada Railroad between Lake Station and Fort Ticonderoga, locomotive with workers on flat cars; Albany Peat Co.'s works; an Indian encampment; men camping at Camp Manhattan.
  - New York--Lake George--Fort William Henry Hotel, [1865-1885] (Box 25)
    Identifier: PR-065-0245
    Fort William Henry Hotel before and after alterations: looking at the hotel from the lake and from the steamboat landing; interior views including the office and the parlor; the piazza with visitors; looking toward the lake and the landing, fountain and visitors in the foreground; visitors on stagecoaches in front of the hotel; views from the hotel of the grounds, stages, lake beyond.
    22 items
  - New York--Lake Mahopac, [1870] (Box 25)
    Identifier: PR-065-0246
    Lake Mahopac: views on the lake, including boaters, islands, workers cutting ice; a road near the lake; water lilies in bloom; people sitting on a porch, probably at Thompson's Hotel, women reading and doing needlework, man holding yarn for a woman; three young couples on the porch views of the hotel; group playing croquet; farm yard with chickens and man holding a horse; group playing croquet in front of a house or hotel with fountain in front; woman watering flowers; views in a garden, including a view of a rose bush in bloom; Engine 15, N.Y.H.& A. Railroad at the station.
  - New York--Lake Mohunk, [1870-1885] (Box 25)
    Identifier: PR-065-0247